Christos Zenonos

Telephone (Mobile)

07969299267

Email Address

christos_zenonos@hotmail.com

Dedicated and hardworking developer, with a 2.1 degree in Computing BSc (Hons) and years of experience working within an agile environment. Fully competent full stack developer with experience in both front end and back end teams. I am very enthusiastic hard working and focused individual. I always strive to learn and better my skillset. and am highly adaptable to many different environments, expectations and workflows

My Skills

- AngularJS (1&2) UI & UX development GIT/SVN OO JavaScript CSS (LESS/SASS/SCSS) Responsive Design
- Bootstrap Webpack HTML5 Typescript Jade/Pug jQuery MySQL Mustache Grunt Gulp Node.js
- Express JS Babel Agile & Scrum Methodology Canvas HammerJS Protractor UnderscoreJs mongoDb
- lodash NPM Yarn Apache Nginx PHP Zend Freemarker Twig Swig

Employment History

Javascript/Frontend Developer (Contractor)

The Workshop January 2017- Present

Key technologies used: • UI & UX development • HTML5 • CSS (SASS/SCSS) • Responsive Design • AngularJS (1&2)

- Typescript GIT OO JavaScript Bootstrap (3 & 4) Webpack Typescript jQuery Mustache Grunt Gulp
- Babel HammerJS Protractor UnderscoreJs Canvas LoDash Agile & Scrum Methodology NPM Swig

Tasked with delivering an API library of components, highly focused on UI & UX and designed to be highly customizable, highly reusable, fully functional, mobile first UI prototypes. Amongst the components that I personally develop, the most noticeable are the search and carousel components. All components are fully responsive, working across a variety of browsers. Using good clean HTML5 CSS and Javascript.

Components where written in Angular, Angular 2, JQuery, Vanilla Javascript and HammerJS

Javascript/Frontend Developer (Contractor)

PulseLive November 2016- January 2017 (3 months)

Key technologies used: • UI & UX development • OO JavaScript • CSS (LESS/SASS/SCSS) • HTML5 • Responsive Design • Bootstrap 3 • Webpack • Freemarker • jQuery • Mustache • Grunt • Gulp • Babel • Agile & Scrum Methodology • UnderscoreJs • Lodash • NPM• GIT

Part of a team to modernize and rebrand the International Cricket Council website (www.icc-cricket.com)
I was tasked with personally delivering a fully responsive frontend solution for the ranking and match predictor, from scratch using only OO Javascript and underscoreJS templating

(https://www.icc-cricket.com/rankings/mens/rankings-predictor/test)

The predictor consists of a ranking table and match fixtures with a usable interface that allowed users to make match predictions and to dynamically change the ranking table based on these predictions.

Changes in team's positions where indicated by physically updating the order displayed in the rankings table and showing a green up arrow icon alongside teams that had increased in position and a red down arrow icon alongside teams that had decreased in position

The solution also allowed for the users predictions to persist even after refresh, if the end client so wished for this functionality.

Html was rendered via freemarker templating language

Other tasks involve, fixing various JavaScript bugs and rewriting JavaScript functions to be mobile friendly.

Frontend developer

Quidco 2015 – 2016

Key technologies used: • AngularJS (1) • UI & UX development • GIT • OO JavaScript • CSS (LESS/SASS/SCSS)

- Responsive Design Bootstrap Webpack HTML5 jQuery Grunt Gulp Node.js Express JS Babel
- Agile & Scrum Methodology Protractor UnderscoreJs lodash NPM

Worked with the frontend team to deliver http://www.shoop.fr (Quidco's French brand)

Shoop is a mobile first, fully responsive front end Angularjs app which sits on top of a NodeJS middleware layer, which in turn communicates to an API driven backend.

I was also tasked in creating a native cashback notification toolbar of which I was solely tasked with delivering. The toolbar interacts and communicates with the Shoop angular app, using the postmessage protocol, to notify a user if the site they're on has cashback available, if they've already activated their cashback & how much cashback they have activated, as well as a pop up panel view to view their current activity, current deals, search merchants etc. https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/mon-alerte-shoop/bflhepcnocdmbpaoicnbfipcdopbpmhc

Quidco is also in the process of rebranding their site and their German site (Qipu), to look and feel like their French counterpart (Shoop) . For this project myself and my team have created static prototype of every current Quidco and Qipu page, as well as moving the current Quidco codebase to an API backend and Nodejs/Angularjs front end architecture. Of which I am implementing the front end.

Developer

Quidco 2013 - 2016

Key technologies used: • AngularJS (1) • UI & UX development • GIT/SVN • OO JavaScript • CSS (LESS/SASS/SCSS)

- Responsive Design Bootstrap Webpack HTML5 ¡Query MySQL Grunt Gulp lodash NPM PHP
- Agile & Scrum Methodology Apache Nginx Zend Twig

Tasked with completing many projects, with different timescales, both large and small. Including coding for the back end (writing of PHP, Zend, MySQL) and the front end (writing the responsive HTML/Twig, CSS JQuery Angularjs Javascript) Noteable projects I was involved in are:

Working and managing the team to rebrand the entire site, as well as creating a UI prototype of every component Rewriting the entire site in bootstrap 2, with responsive design, and then later to bootstrap 3 Migrating the DAO layer to utilize parametrized queries and updating MySQL queries to improve performance. Migrating the wallet functionality into a wallet micro service.

Writing the logic for the promotion engine, offers, usergroups, payment system, widget system and others. Managing and setting up the vagrant environment that we use for development Writing the onboarding and Quidco compare front end services (angularjs)

Quidco - Junior Developer London, England 2011 - 2012

Education and Training History

Bournemouth University (2013) - Computer Science, (BSc) - Second Class Honours, Upper Division (2:1) **Ashmole School (**2009) – 3 A levels, 4 AS levels **Highlands School (**2007) - 10 GCSE Passes (Including English, Mathematics and Science)